<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>alobbs.com</title><link>https://alobbs.com/</link><description>Recent content on alobbs.com</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Thu, 28 Aug 2025 04:29:49 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://alobbs.com/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>2025-08-28 Briefing</title><link>https://alobbs.com/post/2025-08-28/</link><pubDate>Thu, 28 Aug 2025 00:29:39 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://alobbs.com/post/2025-08-28/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;Nvidia exceeded Q2 earnings with $46.74 billion, driven by data center AI growth, but issued a cautious outlook amid China sales uncertainties and US restrictions. EchoStar sold spectrum to AT&amp;amp;T for $23 billion to expand 5G, while Neuralink’s first human implant has restored movement, transforming lives.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>2025-08-26 Briefing</title><link>https://alobbs.com/post/2025-08-26/</link><pubDate>Tue, 26 Aug 2025 22:07:57 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://alobbs.com/post/2025-08-26/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;Google unveiled scalable liquid cooling for AI data centers at Hot Chips 2025, emphasizing water’s high thermal conductivity and maintenance protocols to meet AI heat demands, alongside new security silicon from Microsoft and critical patches for Citrix, Docker, and Google’s Gemini AI models. Meanwhile, Nevada recovers from a cyberattack, and legislation efforts target ghost job postings and AI safety.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>2025-08-25 Briefing</title><link>https://alobbs.com/post/2025-08-25/</link><pubDate>Mon, 25 Aug 2025 22:19:44 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://alobbs.com/post/2025-08-25/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;Today’s news highlights include OpenAI’s ambitious plan to boost GPU capacity to 100 million by 2025, Nvidia’s launch of advanced robotics chips supporting real-time AI inference, and the US government’s strategic investment in Intel through an $8.9 billion stake to secure CHIPS funding. Additionally, Google will require developer verification for all Android app installations starting in 2026 amid rising cybersecurity concerns.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>2025-08-24 Briefing</title><link>https://alobbs.com/post/2025-08-24/</link><pubDate>Sun, 24 Aug 2025 22:01:53 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://alobbs.com/post/2025-08-24/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;Telefonica&amp;rsquo;s covert DNS manipulation aimed at reducing transparency was exposed, while RIKEN and Nvidia announced plans for the zetta-scale FugakuNEXT supercomputer. Meanwhile, US authorities charged a 22-year-old with operating a massive DDoS botnet, and Elon Musk’s xAI open sourced Grok 2.5 amid ongoing licensing debates.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>2025-08-23 Briefing</title><link>https://alobbs.com/post/2025-08-23/</link><pubDate>Sat, 23 Aug 2025 22:04:29 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://alobbs.com/post/2025-08-23/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;Today’s top stories include the US government’s $8.9 billion stake in Intel to bolster semiconductor leadership, the court’s upholding of T-Mobile’s $92 million fine for selling customer data, and AWS’s significant updates enhancing service flexibility and cost efficiency. Additionally, AI’s role in content moderation and enterprise projects faces scrutiny amid rising investment and adoption challenges.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>2025-08-22 Briefing</title><link>https://alobbs.com/post/2025-08-22/</link><pubDate>Fri, 22 Aug 2025 22:05:49 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://alobbs.com/post/2025-08-22/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;Today’s top stories include the US government’s $8.9 billion investment in Intel to bolster domestic chip manufacturing, a major DDoS attack on Arch Linux, and Waymo’s debut autonomous vehicle tests in NYC. Additionally, Microsoft’s Windows update caused streaming issues, and OpenAI warns that AGI could make money obsolete amid soaring AI investments.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>2025-08-21 Briefing</title><link>https://alobbs.com/post/2025-08-21/</link><pubDate>Thu, 21 Aug 2025 00:08:18 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://alobbs.com/post/2025-08-21/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;Today’s top news includes significant security updates: Commvault patched critical RCE bugs exploitable via path traversal and API bypass, and Amazon fixed vulnerabilities in its VS Code extension to prevent data leaks. Additionally, the Russian FSB exploited a Cisco bug to access critical infrastructure, raising global security concerns.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>2025-08-20 Briefing</title><link>https://alobbs.com/post/2025-08-20/</link><pubDate>Wed, 20 Aug 2025 00:06:19 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://alobbs.com/post/2025-08-20/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;Researchers exploited a vulnerability in CodeRabbit to access 1 million repositories, including private ones, highlighting critical security risks. Meanwhile, Foxconn&amp;rsquo;s AI and cloud server revenue surpassed iPhone assembly in 2025, signaling a major shift toward AI infrastructure dominance. Additionally, Wyoming launched its first state-backed stablecoin across seven blockchains, marking progress in digital currency adoption.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>2025-08-19 Briefing</title><link>https://alobbs.com/post/2025-08-19/</link><pubDate>Tue, 19 Aug 2025 00:04:35 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://alobbs.com/post/2025-08-19/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;Today’s headlines highlight Anna’s Archive surpassing 100 million files amid security threats, SoftBank’s $2 billion investment in Intel boosting AI and semiconductor growth, and China-US tensions escalating over GPU tracking and espionage concerns. Additionally, AI regulation, corporate governance issues, and technological advances in gaming and electric vehicle recycling made significant impacts.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>2025-08-18 Briefing</title><link>https://alobbs.com/post/2025-08-18/</link><pubDate>Mon, 18 Aug 2025 00:33:26 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://alobbs.com/post/2025-08-18/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;Today’s highlights include Tesla’s Robotaxi facing safety scrutiny from ex-Waymo CEO, escalating AI-driven cyberattacks with hackers and defenders leveraging large language models, Google fined in Australia for anti-competitive deals, and OpenAI recruiting Democratic insiders to influence regulation and secure major funding.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>2025-08-17 Briefing</title><link>https://alobbs.com/post/2025-08-17/</link><pubDate>Sun, 17 Aug 2025 00:17:58 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://alobbs.com/post/2025-08-17/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;Today’s highlights include Git 2.43&amp;rsquo;s new large file handling features, a decade-long Wikipedia campaign to inflate David Woodard’s profile, and OpenAI’s GPT-OSS-120B showing inconsistent performance across providers. Additionally, the Ritman Library digitized 2,178 occult books, and UK plans to implement AI crime prediction tools by 2030 amid privacy concerns.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>2025-08-16 Briefing</title><link>https://alobbs.com/post/2025-08-16/</link><pubDate>Sat, 16 Aug 2025 03:23:44 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://alobbs.com/post/2025-08-16/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;Today’s top news highlights include the disabling of Hyundai Kona EV’s telematics to prevent data sharing, OpenFreeMap’s handling of 3 billion requests in a day, the launch of NGINX’s native ACME support for automated SSL, and the release of GPT-5 with advanced reasoning and safety features. Additionally, Monero faces a major 51% attack, while Meta undergoes its fourth AI restructuring, reflecting rapid industry shifts.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>2025-08-03 Briefing</title><link>https://alobbs.com/post/2025-08-03/</link><pubDate>Sun, 03 Aug 2025 23:47:16 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://alobbs.com/post/2025-08-03/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;Today’s tech landscape sees a surge in AI-driven infrastructure challenges, with data centers facing capacity and cost pressures amid a booming AI economy. Meanwhile, China’s IPv6 adoption hits record levels, and Apple begins developing a lightweight AI to rival ChatGPT, signaling significant advancements in digital innovation and global connectivity.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>2025-08-02 Briefing</title><link>https://alobbs.com/post/2025-08-02/</link><pubDate>Sat, 02 Aug 2025 22:03:10 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://alobbs.com/post/2025-08-02/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;Today’s headlines highlight the expansion of Beijing-linked cyber espionage tools through Shanghai Firetech’s new patents, Robinhood’s ambitious plans to dominate digital finance with crypto and AI, critical security flaws in US infrastructure risking safety, and Meta’s failed bid to lure top AI talent with a billion-dollar offer.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>2025-08-01 Briefing</title><link>https://alobbs.com/post/2025-08-01/</link><pubDate>Fri, 01 Aug 2025 22:04:22 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://alobbs.com/post/2025-08-01/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;Ubiquiti&amp;rsquo;s UniFi OS Server enters early access, enabling users to self-host their entire network stack. Meanwhile, China accuses US hackers of exploiting a Microsoft zero-day to steal military data, and Google unveils Gemini 2.5 Deep Think, achieving IMO gold standards. Apple emphasizes AI investment, signaling a major strategic shift.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>2025-07-30 Briefing</title><link>https://alobbs.com/post/2025-07-30/</link><pubDate>Wed, 30 Jul 2025 20:07:38 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://alobbs.com/post/2025-07-30/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;Today’s top stories include Microsoft’s Q4 earnings surpassing expectations with over $76 billion in revenue, driven by cloud and AI growth, and Meta’s $72 billion investment in AI infrastructure aiming to develop personal superintelligence by 2030. Meanwhile, Minnesota declared a state of emergency following a coordinated cyberattack on Saint Paul.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>2025-07-23 Briefing</title><link>https://alobbs.com/post/2025-07-23/</link><pubDate>Wed, 23 Jul 2025 16:04:45 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://alobbs.com/post/2025-07-23/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;Today’s tech landscape saw significant breakthroughs with AI, including Aeneas revolutionizing ancient inscription interpretation, while the White House unveiled a sweeping AI development plan. Meanwhile, cybersecurity threats escalated with Amazon’s ‘Q’ AI compromised, and over 400 organizations targeted by Chinese hackers exploiting SharePoint vulnerabilities.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>2025-07-22 Briefing</title><link>https://alobbs.com/post/2025-07-22/</link><pubDate>Tue, 22 Jul 2025 16:06:38 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://alobbs.com/post/2025-07-22/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;Hackers exploited a critical SharePoint zero-day, affecting over 54 organizations worldwide, including U.S. agencies and international targets. Microsoft rushed emergency patches as active exploits pose significant security risks, highlighting urgent vulnerabilities in on-premises SharePoint servers.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>2025-07-21 Briefing</title><link>https://alobbs.com/post/2025-07-21/</link><pubDate>Mon, 21 Jul 2025 16:16:53 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://alobbs.com/post/2025-07-21/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;Today’s tech landscape saw critical security updates for SharePoint amid active exploits, Nvidia supporting RISC-V for AI and HPC, and industry leaders pushing asset tokenization to expand markets. Meanwhile, Alaska Airlines faced a major IT outage, and AI continues to evolve software jobs without replacing engineers, shaping the future of technology and cybersecurity.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>2025-07-20 Briefing</title><link>https://alobbs.com/post/2025-07-20/</link><pubDate>Sun, 20 Jul 2025 16:15:40 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://alobbs.com/post/2025-07-20/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;Today’s headlines highlight the launch of Prime-One Fiber ISP in Michigan, challenging Comcast with gigabit speeds and expansion plans, and Amazon Ring’s rollback of privacy reforms to expand police access and AI surveillance, raising civil liberties concerns.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>2025-07-19 Briefing</title><link>https://alobbs.com/post/2025-07-19/</link><pubDate>Sat, 19 Jul 2025 01:34:27 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://alobbs.com/post/2025-07-19/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;Today’s tech landscape saw significant advances in AI with OpenAI launching autonomous ChatGPT agents capable of executing complex tasks, while Meta and the EU remain at odds over AI regulation and safety guidelines. Meanwhile, TSMC and Rapidus accelerate cutting-edge chip manufacturing in the US, and the FCC proposes new rules to secure undersea internet cables amid geopolitical tensions.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>2025-07-16 Briefing</title><link>https://alobbs.com/post/2025-07-16/</link><pubDate>Wed, 16 Jul 2025 22:59:21 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://alobbs.com/post/2025-07-16/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;Today’s highlights include Cloudflare’s DNS outage caused by a legacy configuration error, impacting global internet access, and Linux surpassing 5% US desktop market share amid Windows decline. Additionally, Ukrainian hackers destroyed 47TB of Russian drone data, and Google plans to replace ChromeOS with Android for better device integration.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>2025-07-15 Briefing</title><link>https://alobbs.com/post/2025-07-15/</link><pubDate>Tue, 15 Jul 2025 22:17:33 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://alobbs.com/post/2025-07-15/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;Today’s top news highlights include the patching of a Chrome bug that bypassed adblock restrictions, Apple’s $500 million investment in US rare-earth manufacturing, Nvidia and AMD resuming AI chip sales to China, Meta’s rapid expansion of AI data centers, and the launch of xAI’s powerful Grok 4 model. Additionally, significant developments in open source AI, security, and industry regulation shaped the tech landscape.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>2025-07-06 Briefing</title><link>https://alobbs.com/post/2025-07-06/</link><pubDate>Sun, 06 Jul 2025 22:01:53 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://alobbs.com/post/2025-07-06/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;Today’s news highlights include the rapid expansion of US AI data centers raising environmental concerns, the disruption of rescue efforts by consumer drones during Texas floods, and a major ransomware attack on Ingram Micro causing widespread operational outages. Additionally, the UK announced a £75.6M debris removal mission for 2028, and Atlassian improved system uptime by migrating databases to Amazon Aurora.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>2025-07-05 Briefing</title><link>https://alobbs.com/post/2025-07-05/</link><pubDate>Sat, 05 Jul 2025 22:46:34 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://alobbs.com/post/2025-07-05/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;Today’s tech headlines highlight a global outage at Ingram Micro caused by a ransomware VPN breach, safety concerns over Tesla&amp;rsquo;s Austin robotaxis, and Colombia’s seizure of a Starlink-enabled narco-submarine. Additionally, AI development continues to accelerate with Meta’s focus on superintelligence and researchers embedding hidden prompts in preprints, raising ethical questions.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>2025-07-04 Briefing</title><link>https://alobbs.com/post/2025-07-04/</link><pubDate>Fri, 04 Jul 2025 22:02:13 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://alobbs.com/post/2025-07-04/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;Today’s highlights include a 14-hour global outage at Ingram Micro disrupting services, Meta and Google advancing privacy-based age verification in Europe, and Microsoft’s plan to remove PowerShell 2.0 from Windows 11. Additionally, the EU moves forward with AI regulations, and TSMC delays its Japan chip plant to bolster U.S. expansion efforts.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>2025-07-03 Briefing</title><link>https://alobbs.com/post/2025-07-03/</link><pubDate>Thu, 03 Jul 2025 22:24:12 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://alobbs.com/post/2025-07-03/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;Today’s tech highlights include Hived’s $42 million funding to expand AI-powered electric parcel delivery in the UK, Meta’s AI superintelligence lab hiring Ilya Sutskever, and Tesla’s Q2 deliveries dropping 14% amid sales challenges. Additionally, researchers expose &amp;ldquo;potemkin understanding&amp;rdquo; in large language models, questioning their true conceptual grasp.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>2025-07-02 Briefing</title><link>https://alobbs.com/post/2025-07-02/</link><pubDate>Wed, 02 Jul 2025 22:06:31 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://alobbs.com/post/2025-07-02/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;OpenAI&amp;rsquo;s significant infrastructure expansion with a 4.5 GW power lease from Oracle highlights the soaring energy demands of AI development, amidst Microsoft’s major layoffs affecting 9,000 employees and strategic shifts, and Cloudflare&amp;rsquo;s new AI data scraping blocks to protect content rights. Meanwhile, the UK considers updating submarine cable laws to counter rising cyber and sabotage threats.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>2025-07-01 Briefing</title><link>https://alobbs.com/post/2025-07-01/</link><pubDate>Tue, 01 Jul 2025 22:05:06 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://alobbs.com/post/2025-07-01/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;Today’s top news highlights include Cloudflare’s launch of a pay-per-crawl marketplace to monetize AI web scraping, Meta’s aggressive AI talent recruitment offering up to $300 million per researcher, and NOAA’s shutdown of the crucial DMSP satellite program risking vital hurricane and polar ice data. Additionally, significant industry shifts include EU’s €20 billion fund for AI gigafactories and Figma’s NYSE IPO filing amid rising AI and R&amp;amp;D costs.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>2025-06-28 Briefing</title><link>https://alobbs.com/post/2025-06-28/</link><pubDate>Sat, 28 Jun 2025 22:15:45 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://alobbs.com/post/2025-06-28/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;Deno&amp;rsquo;s legal battle over the &amp;ldquo;JavaScript&amp;rdquo; trademark was dismissed, raising the possibility of the language becoming public domain. Meanwhile, Meta hires top AI researchers from OpenAI, and Reddit sues Anthropic over data scraping while launching its own AI platform. Tesla achieves its first fully autonomous vehicle delivery, highlighting rapid progress in driverless tech.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>2025-06-27 Briefing</title><link>https://alobbs.com/post/2025-06-27/</link><pubDate>Fri, 27 Jun 2025 22:44:24 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://alobbs.com/post/2025-06-27/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;Today’s top highlights include Meta’s $29 billion AI data center funding push, SteamOS outperforming Windows 11 in gaming on Lenovo devices, and US AI data centers threatening grid capacity with projected 70% power consumption by 2035. Additionally, Germany investigates US hyperscalers’ dominance, and Denmark proposes rights over body features to combat deepfakes.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>2025-06-22 Briefing</title><link>https://alobbs.com/post/2025-06-22/</link><pubDate>Sun, 22 Jun 2025 23:09:48 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://alobbs.com/post/2025-06-22/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;Tesla launched its fully autonomous robotaxi service in Austin, offering rides for a flat fee of $4.20, marking a significant step in self-driving technology and regulatory progress. The service is scalable, uses only cameras, and requires no specialized equipment, signaling a new era for autonomous mobility.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>2025-06-19 Briefing</title><link>https://alobbs.com/post/2025-06-19/</link><pubDate>Thu, 19 Jun 2025 19:10:05 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://alobbs.com/post/2025-06-19/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;Today’s top stories include Google’s Pixel 10 switching to TSMC for its Tensor G5 chip amidst Samsung’s yield issues, Iran’s internet shutdown amid alleged Israeli cyberattacks, and the US offering a $10 million bounty on Iranian hacking groups targeting critical infrastructure. Additionally, AI’s environmental impact and cognitive effects remain a major focus.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>2025-06-18 Briefing</title><link>https://alobbs.com/post/2025-06-18/</link><pubDate>Wed, 18 Jun 2025 02:32:58 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://alobbs.com/post/2025-06-18/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;Today’s tech landscape highlights resilience through Europe&amp;rsquo;s innovative LoRa mesh networks, escalating geopolitical tensions with Taiwan sanctions and US-China dynamics, major cloud security upgrades by AWS, and significant layoffs at Intel and Disney. Meanwhile, Google, Meta, and Honda push AI advancements, while companies like xAI and Salesforce grapple with soaring costs and funding challenges.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>2025-06-15 Briefing</title><link>https://alobbs.com/post/2025-06-15/</link><pubDate>Sun, 15 Jun 2025 18:36:08 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://alobbs.com/post/2025-06-15/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;Today’s tech highlights include the launch of Android 16 with live notifications and enhanced security, Apple&amp;rsquo;s debut of Liquid Glass for immersive interfaces, and Google Cloud&amp;rsquo;s introduction of Nvidia RTX PRO 6000 VMs propelling AI workloads. Meanwhile, Meta&amp;rsquo;s massive $14.3B investment in Scale AI signals fierce industry AI competition.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>2025-06-08 Briefing</title><link>https://alobbs.com/post/2025-06-08/</link><pubDate>Sun, 08 Jun 2025 09:36:49 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://alobbs.com/post/2025-06-08/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;Today’s news highlights include the debunking of misconceptions in aviation data complexity, the launch of the Linux Foundation’s FAIR Package Manager for decentralized WordPress security, and OpenAI’s rollout of personalized AI assistants in higher education. Additionally, Japanese researchers introduced biodegradable transparent cellulose paper, and Mistral AI secured major contracts amid Europe&amp;rsquo;s AI growth push.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>2025-06-07 Briefing</title><link>https://alobbs.com/post/2025-06-07/</link><pubDate>Sat, 07 Jun 2025 10:17:44 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://alobbs.com/post/2025-06-07/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;Tesla seeks to block the disclosure of crash data over concerns it could harm its competitive advantage, amid rising scrutiny of its autonomous vehicle safety. Meanwhile, GitLab dramatically reduced backup times from 48 hours to 41 minutes by fixing a longstanding Git reference issue, showcasing significant progress in internet infrastructure resilience.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>2025-06-05 Briefing</title><link>https://alobbs.com/post/2025-06-05/</link><pubDate>Thu, 05 Jun 2025 11:32:46 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://alobbs.com/post/2025-06-05/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;GlobalFoundries announced a $3 billion investment to expand US chip manufacturing, boosting domestic supply amid US tariffs and supply chain concerns. This move enhances advanced semiconductor production, focusing on photonics and GaN technologies, strengthening America&amp;rsquo;s position in the global chip industry.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>2025-06-04 Briefing</title><link>https://alobbs.com/post/2025-06-04/</link><pubDate>Wed, 04 Jun 2025 09:44:58 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://alobbs.com/post/2025-06-04/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;Today’s top stories include Meta and Yandex apps exploiting Android localhost ports for user tracking, TikTok banning the &amp;lsquo;SkinnyTok&amp;rsquo; hashtag worldwide under French pressure, and Google releasing an emergency update to patch a critical Chrome vulnerability. Additionally, AWS announced a new European Sovereign Cloud to address data sovereignty concerns.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>2025-06-03 Briefing</title><link>https://alobbs.com/post/2025-06-03/</link><pubDate>Tue, 03 Jun 2025 12:01:49 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://alobbs.com/post/2025-06-03/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;Today’s top news includes xAI’s $300 million investment to embed Elon Musk’s Grok AI into Telegram, Walmart’s $580 million Azure spending signaling a major cloud partnership, and the revelation that AI models from Anthropic and OpenAI exhibit deceptive behaviors to avoid shutdowns, raising safety concerns.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>2025-05-29 Briefing</title><link>https://alobbs.com/post/2025-05-29/</link><pubDate>Thu, 29 May 2025 19:31:22 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://alobbs.com/post/2025-05-29/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;Today’s headlines highlight Nvidia’s surpassing earnings driven by data center growth, the EU’s crackdown on Apple’s anti-steering rules, and AI’s potential to eliminate half of white-collar jobs, raising economic and regulatory concerns amid rapid technological advancements.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>2025-05-28 Briefing</title><link>https://alobbs.com/post/2025-05-28/</link><pubDate>Wed, 28 May 2025 17:05:39 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://alobbs.com/post/2025-05-28/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;Today’s tech news highlights include the EU&amp;rsquo;s demand for Apple to comply with App Store rules within 30 days, Oracle&amp;rsquo;s $40 billion investment in Nvidia GPUs for OpenAI’s Texas data center amid power concerns, and the launch of Aurora&amp;rsquo;s first autonomous semi-truck on U.S. highways, signaling significant advancements and regulatory challenges in infrastructure and AI-driven innovation.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>2025-05-27 Briefing</title><link>https://alobbs.com/post/2025-05-27/</link><pubDate>Tue, 27 May 2025 21:27:06 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://alobbs.com/post/2025-05-27/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;Today’s headlines highlight critical vulnerabilities in GitHub MCP risking private data exposure, NTT’s $10 billion investment in AI-ready infrastructure, Salesforce’s $8 billion acquisition of Informatica to boost AI capabilities, and the launch of Mistral’s new LLM-powered Agents API. Additionally, Meta restructures AI teams to accelerate product development amid industry shifts.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>2025-05-26 Briefing</title><link>https://alobbs.com/post/2025-05-26/</link><pubDate>Mon, 26 May 2025 21:19:54 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://alobbs.com/post/2025-05-26/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;Today’s top news includes OpenAI’s $6.5 billion acquisition of Jony Ive’s startup, signaling a major shift in AI hardware and design strategy. Google announced Gemini Diffusion, a faster, error-correcting LLM, while industry concerns grow over talent drain at Meta’s Llama team. Meanwhile, European data centers focus on sustainability, and cybersecurity alerts warn of zero-day exploits in Azure.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>2025-05-21 Briefing</title><link>https://alobbs.com/post/2025-05-21/</link><pubDate>Wed, 21 May 2025 17:40:01 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://alobbs.com/post/2025-05-21/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;Today’s top stories include Google’s expansion of sovereign cloud services to host US Top Secret data, Brazilian researchers scraping over 2 billion Discord messages raising privacy concerns, and Nvidia’s CEO criticizing US-China AI chip export restrictions as a policy failure fueling Chinese innovation.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>2025-05-20 Briefing</title><link>https://alobbs.com/post/2025-05-20/</link><pubDate>Tue, 20 May 2025 19:20:52 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://alobbs.com/post/2025-05-20/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;Today’s tech news highlights include the leak of 410GB of plaintext chats from US officials via TeleMessage, Google’s launch of Project Mariner AI for web browsing, and Waymo’s safer autonomous driving demonstration contrasting Tesla’s FSD failure. Additionally, OpenSource efforts like Microsoft’s open WSL code and France’s adoption of UN open source principles mark significant advancements.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>2025-05-18 Briefing</title><link>https://alobbs.com/post/2025-05-18/</link><pubDate>Sun, 18 May 2025 14:46:57 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://alobbs.com/post/2025-05-18/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;Today’s highlights include Jetrelay’s breakthrough 10 Gbps broadcast using Linux kernel features, the launch of GNU Taler 1.0 boosting digital cash security in Switzerland, and US government app breach exposing sensitive data within minutes. Additionally, concerns grow over privacy risks from Postman logs and threats of exits by Proton and NymVPN over Swiss surveillance laws.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>2025-05-17 Briefing</title><link>https://alobbs.com/post/2025-05-17/</link><pubDate>Sat, 17 May 2025 20:42:47 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://alobbs.com/post/2025-05-17/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;Today’s top news highlights include Microsoft’s workforce reduction affecting key AI and developer roles amid organizational restructuring, Nvidia’s unveiling of advanced Blackwell GPUs driving AI innovation, and the US scrutinizing Apple’s AI partnership with Alibaba over security concerns. Additionally, Google’s new Gemini 2.5 enhances data querying accuracy, and Epic Games seeks court enforcement to reinstate Fortnite on the App Store.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>2025-05-16 Briefing</title><link>https://alobbs.com/post/2025-05-16/</link><pubDate>Fri, 16 May 2025 16:01:25 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://alobbs.com/post/2025-05-16/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;Today’s top stories include Linux 6.15 adding Apple Silicon support, AWS transforming VMware migration from weeks to minutes with AI, and a groundbreaking personalized CRISPR therapy curing a baby with a rare genetic disorder. Additionally, Microsoft faces EU delays, UK approves a Green Belt data center, and AI cybersecurity threats continue to rise.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>2025-05-15 Briefing</title><link>https://alobbs.com/post/2025-05-15/</link><pubDate>Thu, 15 May 2025 16:50:49 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://alobbs.com/post/2025-05-15/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;Today’s tech landscape highlights resilience and innovation, from a securely backed sabotaged NetBSD server to new performance-boosting AI tools like DeepMind’s AlphaEvolve and Nutanix’s enterprise AI support. Meanwhile, industry delays, security upgrades, and policy shifts underscore the evolving challenges and opportunities in internet infrastructure, open source, and AI development.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>2025-05-14 Briefing</title><link>https://alobbs.com/post/2025-05-14/</link><pubDate>Wed, 14 May 2025 16:49:12 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://alobbs.com/post/2025-05-14/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;Today’s headlines include a major setback for Nextcloud’s Android app due to Google’s permission revocation, impacting millions of users, and the announcement of EuroHPC’s upgrade of the Leonardo supercomputer with NVIDIA H100 GPUs for advanced AI workloads. Additionally, Intel aims for a 2027 break-even in its foundry business and Salesforce envisions open source LLMs transforming AI markets.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>2025-05-13 Briefing</title><link>https://alobbs.com/post/2025-05-13/</link><pubDate>Tue, 13 May 2025 15:25:29 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://alobbs.com/post/2025-05-13/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;Today’s highlights include the EU launching a real-time vulnerability database to enhance cybersecurity transparency, Nvidia and AMD partnering with Saudi Arabia for a $10 billion AI data center project, and Apple unveiling new accessibility features for iOS 19 and Vision Pro, reaffirming its commitment to inclusive innovation.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>2025-05-12 Briefing</title><link>https://alobbs.com/post/2025-05-12/</link><pubDate>Mon, 12 May 2025 19:16:49 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://alobbs.com/post/2025-05-12/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;Today’s top news highlights include Google&amp;rsquo;s first icon update in a decade with a vibrant gradient design, the Trump administration’s exploration of AI chip exports to regional allies amid security concerns, and Perplexity’s $200 million Series C funding to expand AI search and chat tools. Additionally, cybersecurity incidents and ongoing challenges in software-defined vehicle development made headlines.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>2025-05-11 Briefing</title><link>https://alobbs.com/post/2025-05-11/</link><pubDate>Sun, 11 May 2025 21:51:03 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://alobbs.com/post/2025-05-11/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;Today’s headlines highlight a critical security flaw in ASUS DriverHub now patched, European court-mandated DNS blocks affecting access to piracy sites, Lloyd’s launch of AI malfunction insurance to cover chatbot errors, and Singapore’s initiative for global AI safety cooperation amid rising geopolitical tensions.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>2025-05-10 Briefing</title><link>https://alobbs.com/post/2025-05-10/</link><pubDate>Sat, 10 May 2025 18:38:04 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://alobbs.com/post/2025-05-10/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;Today’s headlines include the FBI’s indictment of suspects operating a $46 million proxy botnet exploiting outdated routers worldwide, the UK shifting defense spending from US to European firms, and Pope Leo XIV’s call for Vatican II renewal amid AI challenges. Major cybersecurity, geopolitical, and religious developments shape the global landscape.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>2025-05-09 Briefing</title><link>https://alobbs.com/post/2025-05-09/</link><pubDate>Fri, 09 May 2025 18:41:42 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://alobbs.com/post/2025-05-09/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;Today’s news highlights include the US DOJ’s move to break Google’s Chrome monopoly, the US Senate’s chip security bill to prevent smuggling, and 37signals’ significant cost savings by migrating from AWS to on-prem storage. Additionally, CERN’s ALICE experiment confirmed lead-to-gold transmutation, showcasing advances in nuclear physics.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>2025-05-08 Briefing</title><link>https://alobbs.com/post/2025-05-08/</link><pubDate>Thu, 08 May 2025 20:50:04 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://alobbs.com/post/2025-05-08/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;Today’s top stories include openSUSE removing Deepin Desktop over security violations, Nvidia CEO Jensen Huang’s pay rising to nearly $50 million amid record profits, and Meta reigniting stablecoin plans for cross-border payments, signaling significant shifts in open-source security, tech industry earnings, and digital currency ambitions.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>2025-05-05 Briefing</title><link>https://alobbs.com/post/2025-05-05/</link><pubDate>Mon, 05 May 2025 17:44:32 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://alobbs.com/post/2025-05-05/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;Today’s tech news highlights include OpenAI reversing its plan to remain a nonprofit-controlled organization amid regulatory pressure, Google&amp;rsquo;s new AI-focused film initiative aimed at boosting its image, and rising privacy concerns following Meta’s launch of its AI chatbot. Additionally, US job growth outperformed expectations despite a decline in IT sector employment, driven by increased demand for AI skills.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>2025-05-03 Briefing</title><link>https://alobbs.com/post/2025-05-03/</link><pubDate>Sat, 03 May 2025 23:03:59 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://alobbs.com/post/2025-05-03/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;Today’s news highlights include Deno Deploy shrinking its global presence amid declining activity, a major DDoS attack thwarted by Anubis, and a strategic partnership between Waymo and Toyota to advance autonomous vehicles. Additionally, satellite industry growth poses environmental risks, while regulatory and security issues dominate tech and policy updates.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>2025-05-01 Briefing</title><link>https://alobbs.com/post/2025-05-01/</link><pubDate>Thu, 01 May 2025 15:00:36 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://alobbs.com/post/2025-05-01/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;Today’s headlines highlight the US DOJ’s threat to Google’s browser funding, risking web stability, while the Port of Los Angeles warns of a severe inventory crisis amid ongoing US-China trade tensions. Additionally, Nvidia disputes AI chip smuggling claims, and Redis reverts to open source licensing, signaling shifts in global tech and open source landscapes.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>2025-04-30 Briefing</title><link>https://alobbs.com/post/2025-04-30/</link><pubDate>Wed, 30 Apr 2025 13:46:25 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://alobbs.com/post/2025-04-30/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;Today’s tech news highlights include AWS launching second-generation Outposts racks with significant performance gains, Microsoft&amp;rsquo;s commitment to expanding European data centers and safeguarding data sovereignty, and the revelation that up to 30% of Microsoft’s code is now AI-generated, signaling rapid AI adoption across industry leaders.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>2025-04-29 Briefing</title><link>https://alobbs.com/post/2025-04-29/</link><pubDate>Tue, 29 Apr 2025 12:23:40 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://alobbs.com/post/2025-04-29/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;Today’s headlines highlight significant advancements and challenges in internet infrastructure, with Windows 7 logon delays fixed in 2009, and innovative security measures like HAProxy’s Lua-free scraper protection. Meanwhile, China emerges as a major cyber threat to the US, with AI-powered cyberattacks and espionage tactics, underscoring the evolving landscape of cybersecurity threats.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>2025-04-28 Briefing</title><link>https://alobbs.com/post/2025-04-28/</link><pubDate>Mon, 28 Apr 2025 09:29:54 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://alobbs.com/post/2025-04-28/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;Today’s highlights include Huawei’s launch of AI-driven networking solutions to enhance security and performance, Samsung’s admission of plaintext password storage in Galaxy devices, and Apple’s strategic reorganization of its AI teams signaling a shift in its tech focus. Additionally, the appointment of Jia Rong Low as APNIC director general aims to reform internet infrastructure across Asia-Pacific.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>2025-04-27 Briefing</title><link>https://alobbs.com/post/2025-04-27/</link><pubDate>Sun, 27 Apr 2025 09:43:53 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://alobbs.com/post/2025-04-27/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;Today’s headlines include a groundbreaking climate agreement announced at the global summit, promising significant reductions in emissions by 2030. Meanwhile, economic markets reacted positively to new job growth data, and a major breakthrough in medical research offers hope for a rare disease.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>2025-04-26 Briefing</title><link>https://alobbs.com/post/2025-04-26/</link><pubDate>Sat, 26 Apr 2025 14:31:10 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://alobbs.com/post/2025-04-26/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;Discord improved search with Kubernetes and smaller Elasticsearch clusters, speeding up indexing of trillions of messages. Microsoft limited C/C++ extension to official VS Code products, affecting non-Microsoft editors. AI tools reshape workflows. Supabase secured $200M at $2B. DFloat11 cuts LLMs by 30%. XAI (Elon Musk) seeks $20B. UK threatened Wikipedia&amp;rsquo;s tax-exempt status over foreign influence.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>2025-04-25 Briefing</title><link>https://alobbs.com/post/2025-04-25/</link><pubDate>Fri, 25 Apr 2025 10:49:22 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://alobbs.com/post/2025-04-25/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;Intel faces Q2 challenges amid trade tensions, with CEO Tan planning cost cuts and a shift to four-day workweeks. Alphabet reported 12% revenue growth to $90.2 billion in Q1. OpenAI launched gpt-image-1 via API, while Apple plans to move US iPhone assembly to India by 2025. Facebook is tackling spam accounts, Baidu upgraded its Ernie AI models, and Ziff Davis sued OpenAI for copyright infringement.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>2025-04-24 Briefing</title><link>https://alobbs.com/post/2025-04-24/</link><pubDate>Thu, 24 Apr 2025 12:29:57 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://alobbs.com/post/2025-04-24/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;EU fines Apple €500M and Meta €200M for DMA violations, sparking US-EU tensions. Bluesky implemented censorship in Turkey. Security concerns emerged at NLRB after DOGE employees allegedly used GitHub code to extract sensitive data. A study confirms Rust&amp;rsquo;s security advantages. Adobe released advanced Firefly AI models for image and video generation.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>2025-04-23 Briefing</title><link>https://alobbs.com/post/2025-04-23/</link><pubDate>Wed, 23 Apr 2025 16:00:52 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://alobbs.com/post/2025-04-23/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;Atuin Desktop launched as a local-first runbook editor combining terminal execution with document organization. Sapphire emerged as a Rust-based package manager for macOS. NLnet funded 42 open-source projects promoting privacy and decentralization. Intel plans to cut over 20% of its workforce. The EU fined Apple €500M and Meta €200M for Digital Markets Act violations.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>2025-04-22 Briefing</title><link>https://alobbs.com/post/2025-04-22/</link><pubDate>Tue, 22 Apr 2025 22:33:05 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://alobbs.com/post/2025-04-22/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;Valkey replaces Redis in Arch Linux following license changes; web infrastructure faces increased bot traffic and security concerns; Gemini introduces Veo 2-powered video generation for AI Premium subscribers; Google&amp;rsquo;s Gemma 3 models now optimized for consumer GPUs; US electricity milestone as fossil fuels fall below 50% for first time; and TLS certificate lifetimes will reduce to 47 days by 2029.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item></channel></rss>