<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Posts on alobbs.com</title><link>https://alobbs.com/post/</link><description>Recent content in Posts on alobbs.com</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Sun, 18 May 2025 00:41:44 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://alobbs.com/post/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>2025-05-17 Briefing</title><link>https://alobbs.com/post/2025-05-17/</link><pubDate>Sat, 17 May 2025 20:41:31 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://alobbs.com/post/2025-05-17/</guid><description>&lt;p>The UAE aims to lead AI by 2031 with $200 billion in US deals, building a major AI campus and expanding chip access, while Microsoft unveils Tenant Copilot and Agent Factory to revolutionize organizational AI integration. Nvidia’s latest GPUs power AI breakthroughs across industries, marking a pivotal year in global AI innovation.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>2025-05-16 Briefing</title><link>https://alobbs.com/post/2025-05-16/</link><pubDate>Fri, 16 May 2025 16:01:25 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://alobbs.com/post/2025-05-16/</guid><description>&lt;p>Today’s top stories include Linux 6.15 adding Apple Silicon support, AWS transforming VMware migration from weeks to minutes with AI, and a groundbreaking personalized CRISPR therapy curing a baby with a rare genetic disorder. Additionally, Microsoft faces EU delays, UK approves a Green Belt data center, and AI cybersecurity threats continue to rise.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>2025-05-15 Briefing</title><link>https://alobbs.com/post/2025-05-15/</link><pubDate>Thu, 15 May 2025 16:50:49 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://alobbs.com/post/2025-05-15/</guid><description>&lt;p>Today’s tech landscape highlights resilience and innovation, from a securely backed sabotaged NetBSD server to new performance-boosting AI tools like DeepMind’s AlphaEvolve and Nutanix’s enterprise AI support. Meanwhile, industry delays, security upgrades, and policy shifts underscore the evolving challenges and opportunities in internet infrastructure, open source, and AI development.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>2025-05-14 Briefing</title><link>https://alobbs.com/post/2025-05-14/</link><pubDate>Wed, 14 May 2025 16:49:12 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://alobbs.com/post/2025-05-14/</guid><description>&lt;p>Today’s headlines include a major setback for Nextcloud’s Android app due to Google’s permission revocation, impacting millions of users, and the announcement of EuroHPC’s upgrade of the Leonardo supercomputer with NVIDIA H100 GPUs for advanced AI workloads. Additionally, Intel aims for a 2027 break-even in its foundry business and Salesforce envisions open source LLMs transforming AI markets.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>2025-05-13 Briefing</title><link>https://alobbs.com/post/2025-05-13/</link><pubDate>Tue, 13 May 2025 15:25:29 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://alobbs.com/post/2025-05-13/</guid><description>&lt;p>Today’s highlights include the EU launching a real-time vulnerability database to enhance cybersecurity transparency, Nvidia and AMD partnering with Saudi Arabia for a $10 billion AI data center project, and Apple unveiling new accessibility features for iOS 19 and Vision Pro, reaffirming its commitment to inclusive innovation.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>2025-05-12 Briefing</title><link>https://alobbs.com/post/2025-05-12/</link><pubDate>Mon, 12 May 2025 19:16:49 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://alobbs.com/post/2025-05-12/</guid><description>&lt;p>Today’s top news highlights include Google&amp;rsquo;s first icon update in a decade with a vibrant gradient design, the Trump administration’s exploration of AI chip exports to regional allies amid security concerns, and Perplexity’s $200 million Series C funding to expand AI search and chat tools. Additionally, cybersecurity incidents and ongoing challenges in software-defined vehicle development made headlines.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>2025-05-11 Briefing</title><link>https://alobbs.com/post/2025-05-11/</link><pubDate>Sun, 11 May 2025 21:51:03 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://alobbs.com/post/2025-05-11/</guid><description>&lt;p>Today’s headlines highlight a critical security flaw in ASUS DriverHub now patched, European court-mandated DNS blocks affecting access to piracy sites, Lloyd’s launch of AI malfunction insurance to cover chatbot errors, and Singapore’s initiative for global AI safety cooperation amid rising geopolitical tensions.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>2025-05-10 Briefing</title><link>https://alobbs.com/post/2025-05-10/</link><pubDate>Sat, 10 May 2025 18:38:04 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://alobbs.com/post/2025-05-10/</guid><description>&lt;p>Today’s headlines include the FBI’s indictment of suspects operating a $46 million proxy botnet exploiting outdated routers worldwide, the UK shifting defense spending from US to European firms, and Pope Leo XIV’s call for Vatican II renewal amid AI challenges. Major cybersecurity, geopolitical, and religious developments shape the global landscape.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>2025-05-09 Briefing</title><link>https://alobbs.com/post/2025-05-09/</link><pubDate>Fri, 09 May 2025 18:41:42 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://alobbs.com/post/2025-05-09/</guid><description>&lt;p>Today’s news highlights include the US DOJ’s move to break Google’s Chrome monopoly, the US Senate’s chip security bill to prevent smuggling, and 37signals’ significant cost savings by migrating from AWS to on-prem storage. Additionally, CERN’s ALICE experiment confirmed lead-to-gold transmutation, showcasing advances in nuclear physics.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>2025-05-08 Briefing</title><link>https://alobbs.com/post/2025-05-08/</link><pubDate>Thu, 08 May 2025 20:50:04 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://alobbs.com/post/2025-05-08/</guid><description>&lt;p>Today’s top stories include openSUSE removing Deepin Desktop over security violations, Nvidia CEO Jensen Huang’s pay rising to nearly $50 million amid record profits, and Meta reigniting stablecoin plans for cross-border payments, signaling significant shifts in open-source security, tech industry earnings, and digital currency ambitions.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>2025-05-05 Briefing</title><link>https://alobbs.com/post/2025-05-05/</link><pubDate>Mon, 05 May 2025 17:44:32 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://alobbs.com/post/2025-05-05/</guid><description>&lt;p>Today’s tech news highlights include OpenAI reversing its plan to remain a nonprofit-controlled organization amid regulatory pressure, Google&amp;rsquo;s new AI-focused film initiative aimed at boosting its image, and rising privacy concerns following Meta’s launch of its AI chatbot. Additionally, US job growth outperformed expectations despite a decline in IT sector employment, driven by increased demand for AI skills.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>2025-05-03 Briefing</title><link>https://alobbs.com/post/2025-05-03/</link><pubDate>Sat, 03 May 2025 23:03:59 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://alobbs.com/post/2025-05-03/</guid><description>&lt;p>Today’s news highlights include Deno Deploy shrinking its global presence amid declining activity, a major DDoS attack thwarted by Anubis, and a strategic partnership between Waymo and Toyota to advance autonomous vehicles. Additionally, satellite industry growth poses environmental risks, while regulatory and security issues dominate tech and policy updates.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>2025-05-01 Briefing</title><link>https://alobbs.com/post/2025-05-01/</link><pubDate>Thu, 01 May 2025 15:00:36 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://alobbs.com/post/2025-05-01/</guid><description>&lt;p>Today’s headlines highlight the US DOJ’s threat to Google’s browser funding, risking web stability, while the Port of Los Angeles warns of a severe inventory crisis amid ongoing US-China trade tensions. Additionally, Nvidia disputes AI chip smuggling claims, and Redis reverts to open source licensing, signaling shifts in global tech and open source landscapes.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>2025-04-30 Briefing</title><link>https://alobbs.com/post/2025-04-30/</link><pubDate>Wed, 30 Apr 2025 13:46:25 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://alobbs.com/post/2025-04-30/</guid><description>&lt;p>Today’s tech news highlights include AWS launching second-generation Outposts racks with significant performance gains, Microsoft&amp;rsquo;s commitment to expanding European data centers and safeguarding data sovereignty, and the revelation that up to 30% of Microsoft’s code is now AI-generated, signaling rapid AI adoption across industry leaders.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>2025-04-29 Briefing</title><link>https://alobbs.com/post/2025-04-29/</link><pubDate>Tue, 29 Apr 2025 12:23:40 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://alobbs.com/post/2025-04-29/</guid><description>&lt;p>Today’s headlines highlight significant advancements and challenges in internet infrastructure, with Windows 7 logon delays fixed in 2009, and innovative security measures like HAProxy’s Lua-free scraper protection. Meanwhile, China emerges as a major cyber threat to the US, with AI-powered cyberattacks and espionage tactics, underscoring the evolving landscape of cybersecurity threats.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>2025-04-28 Briefing</title><link>https://alobbs.com/post/2025-04-28/</link><pubDate>Mon, 28 Apr 2025 09:29:54 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://alobbs.com/post/2025-04-28/</guid><description>&lt;p>Today’s highlights include Huawei’s launch of AI-driven networking solutions to enhance security and performance, Samsung’s admission of plaintext password storage in Galaxy devices, and Apple’s strategic reorganization of its AI teams signaling a shift in its tech focus. Additionally, the appointment of Jia Rong Low as APNIC director general aims to reform internet infrastructure across Asia-Pacific.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>2025-04-27 Briefing</title><link>https://alobbs.com/post/2025-04-27/</link><pubDate>Sun, 27 Apr 2025 09:43:53 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://alobbs.com/post/2025-04-27/</guid><description>&lt;p>Today’s headlines include a groundbreaking climate agreement announced at the global summit, promising significant reductions in emissions by 2030. Meanwhile, economic markets reacted positively to new job growth data, and a major breakthrough in medical research offers hope for a rare disease.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>2025-04-26 Briefing</title><link>https://alobbs.com/post/2025-04-26/</link><pubDate>Sat, 26 Apr 2025 14:31:10 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://alobbs.com/post/2025-04-26/</guid><description>&lt;p>Discord improved search with Kubernetes and smaller Elasticsearch clusters, speeding up indexing of trillions of messages. Microsoft limited C/C++ extension to official VS Code products, affecting non-Microsoft editors. AI tools reshape workflows. Supabase secured $200M at $2B. DFloat11 cuts LLMs by 30%. XAI (Elon Musk) seeks $20B. UK threatened Wikipedia&amp;rsquo;s tax-exempt status over foreign influence.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>2025-04-25 Briefing</title><link>https://alobbs.com/post/2025-04-25/</link><pubDate>Fri, 25 Apr 2025 10:49:22 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://alobbs.com/post/2025-04-25/</guid><description>&lt;p>Intel faces Q2 challenges amid trade tensions, with CEO Tan planning cost cuts and a shift to four-day workweeks. Alphabet reported 12% revenue growth to $90.2 billion in Q1. OpenAI launched gpt-image-1 via API, while Apple plans to move US iPhone assembly to India by 2025. Facebook is tackling spam accounts, Baidu upgraded its Ernie AI models, and Ziff Davis sued OpenAI for copyright infringement.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>2025-04-24 Briefing</title><link>https://alobbs.com/post/2025-04-24/</link><pubDate>Thu, 24 Apr 2025 12:29:57 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://alobbs.com/post/2025-04-24/</guid><description>&lt;p>EU fines Apple €500M and Meta €200M for DMA violations, sparking US-EU tensions. Bluesky implemented censorship in Turkey. Security concerns emerged at NLRB after DOGE employees allegedly used GitHub code to extract sensitive data. A study confirms Rust&amp;rsquo;s security advantages. Adobe released advanced Firefly AI models for image and video generation.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>2025-04-23 Briefing</title><link>https://alobbs.com/post/2025-04-23/</link><pubDate>Wed, 23 Apr 2025 16:00:52 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://alobbs.com/post/2025-04-23/</guid><description>&lt;p>Atuin Desktop launched as a local-first runbook editor combining terminal execution with document organization. Sapphire emerged as a Rust-based package manager for macOS. NLnet funded 42 open-source projects promoting privacy and decentralization. Intel plans to cut over 20% of its workforce. The EU fined Apple €500M and Meta €200M for Digital Markets Act violations.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>2025-04-22 Briefing</title><link>https://alobbs.com/post/2025-04-22/</link><pubDate>Tue, 22 Apr 2025 22:33:05 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://alobbs.com/post/2025-04-22/</guid><description>&lt;p>Valkey replaces Redis in Arch Linux following license changes; web infrastructure faces increased bot traffic and security concerns; Gemini introduces Veo 2-powered video generation for AI Premium subscribers; Google&amp;rsquo;s Gemma 3 models now optimized for consumer GPUs; US electricity milestone as fossil fuels fall below 50% for first time; and TLS certificate lifetimes will reduce to 47 days by 2029.&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>