<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Briefing on alobbs.com</title><link>https://alobbs.com/categories/briefing/</link><description>Recent content in Briefing on alobbs.com</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Sun, 27 Apr 2025 00:36:56 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://alobbs.com/categories/briefing/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>2025-04-26 Briefing</title><link>https://alobbs.com/post/2025-04-26/</link><pubDate>Sat, 26 Apr 2025 14:31:10 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://alobbs.com/post/2025-04-26/</guid><description>&lt;p>Discord revolutionized its search infrastructure using Kubernetes and smaller Elasticsearch clusters, enabling faster indexing of trillions of messages. Meanwhile, Microsoft restricted its C/C++ extension for VS Code to official products, impacting non-Microsoft editors. In a broader tech landscape, AI coding tools are reshaping developer workflows, while Supabase secured $200 million in funding at a $2 billion valuation. Additionally, DFloat11 compression reduces LLM sizes by 30%, and Elon Musk’s XAI is reportedly seeking $20 billion in funding. Regulatory concerns also emerged as the UK threatened Wikipedia’s tax-exempt status over foreign influence allegations.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>2025-04-25 Briefing</title><link>https://alobbs.com/post/2025-04-25/</link><pubDate>Fri, 25 Apr 2025 10:49:22 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://alobbs.com/post/2025-04-25/</guid><description>&lt;p>Intel faces Q2 challenges amid trade tensions, with CEO Tan planning cost cuts and a shift to four-day workweeks. Alphabet reported 12% revenue growth to $90.2 billion in Q1. OpenAI launched gpt-image-1 via API, while Apple plans to move US iPhone assembly to India by 2025. Facebook is tackling spam accounts, Baidu upgraded its Ernie AI models, and Ziff Davis sued OpenAI for copyright infringement.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>2025-04-24 Briefing</title><link>https://alobbs.com/post/2025-04-24/</link><pubDate>Thu, 24 Apr 2025 12:29:57 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://alobbs.com/post/2025-04-24/</guid><description>&lt;p>EU fines Apple €500M and Meta €200M for DMA violations, sparking US-EU tensions. Bluesky implemented censorship in Turkey. Security concerns emerged at NLRB after DOGE employees allegedly used GitHub code to extract sensitive data. A study confirms Rust&amp;rsquo;s security advantages. Adobe released advanced Firefly AI models for image and video generation.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>2025-04-23 Briefing</title><link>https://alobbs.com/post/2025-04-23/</link><pubDate>Wed, 23 Apr 2025 16:00:52 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://alobbs.com/post/2025-04-23/</guid><description>&lt;p>Atuin Desktop launched as a local-first runbook editor combining terminal execution with document organization. Sapphire emerged as a Rust-based package manager for macOS. NLnet funded 42 open-source projects promoting privacy and decentralization. Intel plans to cut over 20% of its workforce. The EU fined Apple €500M and Meta €200M for Digital Markets Act violations.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>2025-04-22 Briefing</title><link>https://alobbs.com/post/2025-04-22/</link><pubDate>Tue, 22 Apr 2025 22:33:05 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://alobbs.com/post/2025-04-22/</guid><description>&lt;p>Valkey replaces Redis in Arch Linux following license changes; web infrastructure faces increased bot traffic and security concerns; Gemini introduces Veo 2-powered video generation for AI Premium subscribers; Google&amp;rsquo;s Gemma 3 models now optimized for consumer GPUs; US electricity milestone as fossil fuels fall below 50% for first time; and TLS certificate lifetimes will reduce to 47 days by 2029.&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>